Guide to the Heinz Eulau Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Heinz Eulau papers
undated
SC0697
Eulau, Heinz, 1915-2004.
42 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Biographical/Historical note
Heinz Eulau (1915-2004), the William Bennett Munro Professor of Political Science, Emeritus, was a major figure in American political science and a leading scholar in the fields of legislative research, political representation and electoral behavior.
He was born in Offenbach, Germany, on October 14, 1915 into a German Jewish family whose wide-ranging lineage he and his brother Frank (“in cooperation with cousins of all sorts”) documented in a book on “The Mishpokhe from Eulau-Jilové: Discovering a Remarkably Unremarkable Jewish Family from Germany” (2001). After immigrating to the United States in 1935, he earned his degrees in political science at the University of California in Berkeley: A.B. 1937, M.A. 1938, PhD 1941. Following engagements at the Library of Congress, the U.S. Department of Justice, and The New Republic, he started his academic career at Antioch College in 1947 and joined in 1957 the Stanford Department of Political Science which he chaired twice, 1969-74 and 1981-84, and from which he retired as the William Bennett Munro Professor of Political Science, Emeritus, in 1986. He has held visiting appointments at the University of California at Berkeley, the Institute of Advanced Studies in Vienna, and Erasmus University in Rotterdam.
Eulau was president of the American Political Science Association 1971-72; he founded the Legislative Studies Quarterly in 1976, was active in the behavioral sciences division of the National Research Council (1969-73), chairman of the board of overseers of the National Election Studies (1977-84), and associate director of the Inter-University Consortium for Political and Social Research (1975-78). Awards in his name and honor were created by the American Political Science Association (1986) and the Stanford Institute for the Quantitative Study of Society (2002).
Heinz Eulau is considered one of the founding scholars of what came to be known as the behavioral movement in political science which brought the analytical tools of sociology and psychology to bear on the empirical study of the linkages between individual behavior and political processes. The focus of Eulau’s work was on the patterns and determinants of electoral and legislative behavior and on the politics of political representation. His extensive published work in this area (including Legislative Behavior, 1959; The Behavioral Persuasion in Politics, 1963; Political behavior in America: New Directions, 1966; State Officials and Higher Education [with Harold Quinley and David D. Henry], 1970; Labyrinths of Democracy [with Kenneth Prewitt], 1973; Politics, Self, and Society, 1986) is considered part of the classics of modern political science and has shaped research as well as teaching in the discipline over the past fifty years. He was one of the founders of the influential journal, The American Behavioral Scientist. Many of his students have moved into positions of leadership in the discipline in their own right, including Stanford faculty members Norman Nie and John Ferejohn and Kenneth Prewitt at Columbia, who credit Eulau with directing their early work and with the equally important role of mentoring their entry into the profession.
His 1972 Presidential Address for the American Political Science Association represents one of the discipline’s early reflections on the impact of modern technology and the resulting “skill revolution” on the nature and functioning of political systems. His search for “political processes better adapted to the requirements of a rapidly changing technological society than are participative, representational, and bureaucratic processes alone” led him to the vision of a “consultative commonwealth” where professionalized consultation becomes “the linkage mechanism between democracy and bureaucracy”.
In his later years, Heinz Eulau allowed his impish sense of humor free reign in taking on some of the “fads, foibles and fables” of his colleagues in his 1998 book on “The Politics of Academic Culture”, chapters of which are devoted to such topics as “The Faculty’s Fallacious but Felicitous Faculties, or Nemesis and When Not to Love Thy Colleague as Thyself” or “The Rating, Ranking and Baiting Game, or Don’t Believe All You Read about Yourself Even if True”. The book’s epilogue is entitled “De Mortuis Nil nisi Bonum, or Better Write Your Own Obituary before It Is Too Late” – which Heinz Eulau, forever a man of his word, promptly proceeded to do.
Heinz Eulau’s wife of 58 years, Cleo, passed away shortly after her husband at Stanford Hospital after a long illness. They are survived by their children Peter and Lauren, and three grandchildren. Family, friends, and colleagues gathered for a memorial celebration of the lives of Heinz and Cleo Eulau on March 2, 2004, in Stanford Memorial Church.
Collection Contents
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2004-55
  - Easton Fest (A33), 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Apostacy of David Easton (A33), 1965-1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - International Relations (A34), 1972-1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Humawish (A41), 1949 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Of Bellavior & Institution (A47), 1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The Discipline's Community: The Effects of Method and Market on Research Relevance, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - An Inquiry In Search Of Identity (A48), 1981-1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Illustrations (A50), 1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Teaching Materials (A51), 1959-1986 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Contextomism (A52), 1967-1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Modes & Discip. Development (A53), 1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Action| Citizen's HIP (A28), 1950-1984 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Karps Memoranda (A54), 1958-1978 (Box 1)
  - Idea File (A55), Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Rochester--Contextual Data Follow Up (A56), 1974-1989 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Munro (A58), 1983 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Research Grants and Proposals (A59), 1969-1974 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Public Administration Review (A60), 1967 Jun (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Pending Book Reviews (A62), 1958-1981 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Urban-RURM (A64), 1967-1973 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Notes, Chapter 14 Of Fact (A65), Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Miller Festschrift--Tom Mann (A67), 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence Letter to Heinz (A68), 34480 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Herzog Paper (A72), 1990-1996 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence Cher Lao-Tzu (A70), Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Lippincott Award (A71), 1985 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Annotated Notes of Readings, Undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Annotated Notes of Readings, Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Annotated Notes of Readings, Undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Pluralism (A14), 1990 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Modern Behavioral Approach (Jerusal) (A63), 1996 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Excursions into Biology, 1977-1987 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Masters Model of Human Behavior (A26), Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Various Reflection and Journal pieces by Eulau, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Socrates Library Search, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Table of Contents: Radical and Renegades: Vignettes of Twenty-seven Communist Fellow Travelers in the 1930s, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Dreiser (5), Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Maverick Fellow Traveler: Eastman Chapter 1, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Premature Fellow Traveler: Dell Chapter 2, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Elusive Fellow Traveler: Vorse Chapter 3, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Part II: A Trio of Troubled Novelists, Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Contrarian Fellow Traveler: Dreiser Chapter 4, Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Romantic Fellow Traveler: Anderson Chapter 5, Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Rebellious Fellow Traveler: Dos Passos Chapter 6, Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Part III: A Trio of Aesthetes, Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Reflective Fellow Traveler: Cowley Chapter 7, Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Mercurial Fellow Traveler: Josephson Chapter 8, Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Wayward Fellow Traveler: Burke Chapter 9, Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Pentient Fellow Traveler: Hicks Chapter 10, Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Electic Fellow Traveler: Wilson Chapter 12, Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Library Search Results, Undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Correspondent Current Re: Chapter 12, Undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Non-Political Fellow Traveler: Sherwood Anderson Chapter 5, Undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Sherwood Anderson: Slumming Fellow Traveler Chapter 5, Undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Rebellious Fellow Traveler: John Dos Passos Chapter 6, Undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Penitent Fellow Traveler: Granville Hicks Chapter 10, Undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Vignettes of Twenty-seven Communist Fellow Travelers in the 1930s Chapter Edits, Undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Vignettes of Twenty-seven Communist Fellow Travelers in the 1930s Chapter Edits, Undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Vignettes of Twenty-seven Communist Fellow Travelers in the 1930s Chapter Edits, Undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Vignettes of Twenty-seven Communist Fellow Travelers in the 1930s Chapter Edits, Undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Vignettes of Twenty-seven Communist Fellow Travelers in the 1930s Chapter Edits, Undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Vignettes of Twenty-seven Communist Fellow Travelers in the 1930s Chapter Edits, Undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Sources and References for Vignettes of Twenty-seven Communist Fellow Travelers in the 1930s, Undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Sources and References for Vignettes of Twenty-seven Communist Fellow Travelers in the 1930s, Undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Sources and References for Vignettes of Twenty-seven Communist Fellow Travelers in the 1930s, Undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - The Days of Innocence: Growing Up In A Small Town, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - PB+ Democracy Fact -Value (B11), Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - State of Description + Beating Up on PS (B12), Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Untitled B13, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Basic Applied Research (B14), Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Personal History Addenda (B15), 1978-1976 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - End of Ideology (B16), 1956 July (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Philosophy of Science + Method (B17), Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Jim (James) Farr Correspondence (B18), Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Pioneers (19), Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Kirk, Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - University of Iowa Conference, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Notes for Columbia Studies (B22), Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - CASBS - Role Analysis Seminar (B21), 1957 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - NES Network Paper (B22), Undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Representation (B23), 1982 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Legislative Committees As Interstital Structures In Constitutency Representation: The Case of the American Congress (B23), 1982 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Council Project Proposal (B24), 1964 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Ideas as Projective Systems (B25), 1945-1953 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Class and Party (B26), 1954-1956 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Oral History Project (B27), 1988 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Codebook 08 (B29), Undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Notes/Outlines For Haruard Book (B28), 1972-1978 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Network Project (B30), 1967-1970 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Heinz Eulau's Orienation and Research: A Study of the Behavioral Movement In Political Science (B31), 1974 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Working Paper on Class and Party in Voting Behavior, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Proposal to the National Science Foundation, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - The Atlantic Monthly: The New Intellectual (B35), 1995 Mar (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Writings 1967 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Writings & Notes 1967-1987 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Social Network Analysis and Political Behavior 1967-1984 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Notes & Readings 1969-1986 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - The Congruence Model Revistited, 1987 May 2 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - American State Legislators' Role Orientations Toward Pressure Groups, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Post-Conference Memoranda, Social Networks, Political Behavior, and Political Organization, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Paper, Small Groups in Legislative Poltics: A Potpourri of Comments on a Potpourri of Papers, 29832 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Draft, The Hoover Elite Studies Revisted, Undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Comments, Polling: Mostly Technology, Little Sicence, 1980 Apr. 24 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Paper, On Revolutions That Never Were, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Comments, Congressional Elections Research: Old Themes, New Difficulties, 1980 Jan. 11 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - A Post-Facto Experiment in Contextual Analysis: Of Day and Night-Dwellers, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - The American Journal of Sociology, 1976 Jan. 4 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Standing Committtees in Legislatures: Three Decades of Research, 1984 May 2 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Paper, Policy Represenation as an Emergent: Toward a Situational Analysis, 1977 Sep (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - The Poltical Freedom of African-Americans: A Contextual Analysis of Racial Attitues, Poltical Tolerance, and Individual Liberty, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Memorandum, Community Council, 18674 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Chapter 1, The Long View and The Short, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Notes and paper clippings, Undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Lecture Outline, Ameican Government and Poltics, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Ford Application, Undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Reason and Nature, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Epistem 2.3, Undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Epistem 2.4, Undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Chapter 22, Undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Comments on "On Behavioralism", Undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Recent Developments in the Behavioral Study of Poltics, Copy 1, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - On Behavioralism, 1981 Oct. 7 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Review of "THe Efficacy of Uncertaininty: Sympathetic Overview of Behavioralism", Undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - A Phenomenoligical Critique of The Behavioral Persuasion in Poltics: A Philosophical View, 1971 Sept. 7 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Conentions and Pretentions, Undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - American Political Science Review Vol. 83, Undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - 1987 Book Reviews: Review Essays, Undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - The Political Socialization of American State Legislators, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - The Analysis of Research: A Case of Collaboration in Comparative Study of Legislative Behavior, 1961 May (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Comparative Polticial Analysis: A Methodlogical Note, 1962 Nov (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - The Role of The Representative: Some Empirical Observations On The Teory of Edmund Burke, 1959 Sept (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - The Ecological Basis of Party Systems: The Case of Ohio, 1957 Aug (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - City Councilmen and The Group Struggle: A Typology of Role Orientations, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - David Easton and the Behavioralists A Memoir on Revolutions, So-Called, in Political Science, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - The Congress as Research Arena: An Uneasy Partnership Between History and Polticial Science, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Electoral Survey Data and the Temporal Dimension, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - The Congruence Model Revistited, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Cross Level Challenges for Communication Research, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Social Science at Crossroads, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - The Annals of Research: A Case of Collaboration in Comparative Study of Legislative Behavior, 1961 May. (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Comparative Poltical Analysis: A Methodlogical Notes, 1962 Nov. (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Poltical Socialization and Poltical Roles, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - The Legislator As Specialist, 1960 Sept. (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Bases of Authority in Legislative Bodies: A Comparative Analysis, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Occupational Mobility and Poltical Career, 1962 Sept. 3 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Political Socialization and Poltical Roles, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - American State Legislators' Role Orientations Toward Pressure Groups, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Lobbyists: The Wasted Profession, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Career Perspectives of American State Legislators, Undated (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - PB Concept History, 1957-1985 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - PB Concept History, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Return of State, 1979-1988 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Interdisciplinary vs Specilization, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Honors, Undated (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Objtuary, 1957-1975 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - The ConGuest, 1961-1965 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - The Conservative Complaint, 1960 Sept. (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Predecessors, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Bibliographies, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Pluralisms vs. Marxism, Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Sundry Book Reviews, Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Power and Influence, Undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Theory: Power, Undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Mailing Lists, Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Political Behavior Training Memos, Undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Hoover Institution, Undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Assorted Publishd/Unpublished Papers, Undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Bellagio, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Unanimity Drafts, Notes, Undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Holland - Erasmus, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Legislators & Magistrates, 1965 May 16 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - European Trip, 1979 Nov. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Staff Memoranda, Undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Guggenheim Proposal, Undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Guggenheim Fellowhip, 1979-80 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Iowa Conference, 1969 May 26-30 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - After 30 Years: Pol Sci in IESS, Undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Phi Beta Kappa Lecture Tour, 1980-81 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Ford Fellowship, 1951-52 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Reflections on Theory in Pol. Sci., 1957-58 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Easton, Undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Vienna Roles, Undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Lippmann, Undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Discourses of Politics, Undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Herbert Croly, Undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Lippmann Book, Undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Labyrinths of Democracy (book reviews, correspondence), Undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Harvard Book (Permissions, Contract), Undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Eulogies, Undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Antioch, 1945-1950 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Antioch, 1950-1953 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Personal Items, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Norway Trip, 1976 May 15 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Retiree Health Care, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Stanford University: Reagular and Early Retirees Health & Welfare, 1995 Aug. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Health Documents, Take Care, 1989-1994 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Dissertation, 1941 May 5 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - American Political Science Association 1996 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - He Historical Dates, 1991 Feb. 28 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Travel Vouchers, 1974-1989 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - U.C. Institute of Governmental Studies, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - APSA Award Fund, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - He Stationary, Undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Politics, Self, Society--Reviews, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - NSF Network Budget, 1985 Feb. 28 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Norms Article, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Legislative Norms Article Contract, 1993 Mar. 22 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Almond Oral History, Undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Social Science and the Public Agenda: Reflections on the Relation of Knowledge to Policy in the United States and Abroad, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Extended Eulau Family, 2003 Jan. (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Cranberg Lawyers, 2003 Jan. 10 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Almond, 2001-2003 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Lirbary Books to Take Out, 2003 Jan, 27 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Legislative Studies, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence Norman's Birthday Plans, 2003 Jan. 17 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Ditto Masters for Some Codebooks, 1977-1986 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Political Culture, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Political Science and History, 1986 Feb (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - International Politics, 1977-1987 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Policy, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Public Opinoin, 1980-1988 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Models, 1977-1989 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Case Studies, 1975-1988 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - On Personality, Undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - On Biology, Undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - On Institutions, Undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - On Values, Undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - On Policy, Undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - On Public Administration, Undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - On Behavioralism in Political Science, Undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - On Behavioral and Political Science, Undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - On Political Theory and Political Science, Undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - On Epistemology of Political Science, Undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - American Political Science Association - Letters, Undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Sovereignty: An Institutional Perspective by Krasner + Comments by HE, Undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - The State as Collective Actor, Undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Measurement of Properties, Undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - The Micro-Macro Problem in Epistemological and Ontological Perspective by HE, Undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Rational Choice Notes, Undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Legislative Outputs: Policies, Undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Legislative Elections, Undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Politics, Self and Society, Undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Sage Publications, Undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Article (original) on Elections for Encycl. Brit. (w/ Gibbens), Undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Political Science 400 - Class Notes, Undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Grad Orientation, Fall 1983 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Political Science 400 - Cotter, Undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Tutorial on Communication, Undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Difficulties of Analysis, Undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - The Concept of Role and Political Roles, Undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - The Voter, Elections, and the Polity - draft, Undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Toward a Functional Model of Elections, Undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - The Functional Approach, Undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Orientation, Fall 1980 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Political Science 281a: Empirical Theory, Fall 1965 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - BLAU: The Differentiation of Power by Richard A. Buck, Undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Chapter 7. Micro Analysis: The Argument, Undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Chapter 6. Macro Analysis: The Argument, Undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Micro-Macro "Gap", Undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Chapter 4. Is Ther a Micro-Macro "Gap?": The Problem, Undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Method as Bond and the Competition of Theories, Undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Meaning of Method + Methodology, Undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Method & Biases, Undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Number of Units & Method, Undated (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Epistemology + Ontology, Undated (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Peer Reviews, Undated (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Roger Masters - Notes, Undated (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - MiMa Leftovers, Undated (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Analogies & Metaphors, Undated (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Structure as Concept, Undated (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Interaction, Context, Environment, Undated (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Levels of Abstraction + Scale of Entity, Undated (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Classification as Method, Undated (Box 8, Folder 34)